this video is sponsored by audible
thanks guys
we're kicking off today's episode
floating in a hot tub
surrounded by our wealth of the server
we are kicking off today's episode
in corrales's base this is not my base i
mean it is my base but i'm also in
corrales space and i'm not showing you
how to get in here it's definitely ugly
with all of these
giant diamond blocks so i've been
working on something over here
maui i am recording
i am working on okay
so i have been working on a sewer design
over here but this is how i propose that
the secret base
bros all link up their bases so we
we all have our own little way into the
sewer system
and we we can visit each other secret
bases without exactly knowing where they
are i think that's possible like if you
entered my base through the sewer system
unless you broke through this wall
you wouldn't know where it is so it can
the location can still remain a secret
of course this all falls apart if
corrales finds this but
we'll cross that bridge when we get to
it so what are we going to do today
apart from show off our secret base
well impulse did actually send me a
message
about meeting up at his secret base but
i've got to kind of wait for those guys
to get online before we can do that
so what i'm going to do is a few chores
around the server
before we go and meet them the first one
is
the ultimate chore which is keeping up
with the barge
stock the barge is something that has
to have a lot of off-camera attention
corrales has paid me up over here i've
been collecting plenty of diamonds
all across the board but i can't keep up
with
stock so particularly sand and gravel
they're always always empty and i
thought today
i just get ahead of myself i'd stock up
on so many boxes
20 boxes each so that i don't have to
stock the barge
at least for a couple of days these
hermits know how to get through their
concrete i'm also going to do the same
for logs as well because even though
there's another log shop i actually do
pretty good business with this so
sand gravel logs trading
we're gonna do a quick time lapse i mean
this is
quick time lapse this is gonna be 20
seconds of the video people and it
five hours all right ready let's go
[Music]
and uh i was gonna say we're all stocked
up
i obviously stocked up straight uh
straight after see this is the benefit
we got loads of diamonds and here's the
thing we've got
plenty of backup stock i mean this this
is a really good example of why i needed
to do that time lapse
because this was less than 12 hours
later
and it's already running out
unbelievable
there we go so we've got plenty of sand
plenty of gravel
in reserve this is owner only you can't
go through here and just buy the boxes
you got to buy out of the chests so i've
done
quite a lot of stocking up in the barge
i've gotta add to the profits
things are going pretty well update on
button 2.0
looks like we're almost in the red zone
don't
know how i mean i don't know how long
this has been so
when did this come about week ago we
must be only a few days away
maybe okay so now
we're gonna head back to the base uh no
word from impulse or bdubs yet
so we are going to head back to the base
and get some more chores done
so last episode we worked on
the beautiful interior to the mansion
and i gotta
gotta admit i really really like it it's
grown on me
even more the issue is since i've built
this i haven't really been up here very
much
i have got this thing which i need to
work on i need to finish this
villager farm and the iron golem farm
and all that sort of stuff but i
i just haven't felt like doing this
yeah i haven't i haven't managed to
pluck up the courage
to fix whatever's going on over here
however
it is something that i maybe want to
tackle in the next episode
because this episode i would like to
build
a part that i have been putting off
i want to replicate what i got here
over here it's time for me to
fill in this big hole
and this is partly why episodes take
such a long time
because it's not just about hopping in a
time lapse every few minutes
no no no you need shulker boxes full of
cyan terracotta
full of all the blocks that you might
need for a project
like this so i have
me i have a feeling this won't even cut
it so i may
have to i may have to do this in bits
however i think i do have enough to at
least make
some decent progress i may even
make the slime farm 2.0 over there
but either way i'm not going to focus on
this build all i'm going to do today
is replicate this bit which in itself
looks kind of unfinished and bland
there's no detail here
but i'll you know not a big deal it's
not the focus of the build
but this big hole is an issue
because it's ugly it's
ugly and we need to take care of that
because it's um
it's not great you'll also notice from
that time lapse that i went and made
like a proper
tree farm over here oh that that
small amount of uh gathering logs
was really painful really really painful
but i did get
a good stock of all the different kinds
of vlogs
except acacia but look at that really
really good stuff
so without further ado let's
get into the hole number two
[Music]
have you ever wondered how time lapses
are made on hermitcraft
well today i thought i'd give you a
little bit of the behind the scenes
of what we do so when we want to make a
big
project like our bases or whatever it
may be
in order to make sure we nail it we
often go into
our servers or our single players so we
can mock up a design
in creative mode now sometimes we nail
it first time such as the interior of my
mansion i was really happy with the
first draft
sometimes things take a little longer
than you might expect
one thing i had a particular difficulty
with this season
was the design of grumbot a robot from
earlier in the season who you could talk
to
and i just couldn't figure out what i
wanted him to look like
so here is a version of hermitcraft from
an earlier part in the season
it's a bit of a blast from the past
really you can see that the island is
still mycelium
and take a look here at grumbot there
are multiple designs multiple ways that
granbot could have come
out even one way looks a lot like the
iron giant
eventually i landed on a design that i
was
really happy with once we've got our
design we then head over
to the normal hermitcraft world and then
we
rebuild what we made now there's
something
that all of these things have in common
and that is they take a lot of time
that is where audible comes in nice
segue green you really nailed this one
audible is the leading provider of audio
based
entertainment and i think it's fair to
say that it pretty much
fuels my experience on hermitcraft you
see when you're building something or
time-lapsing
you've kind of got to focus on what
you're building
but it can be quite soul-destroying
going for six hours straight so having
something there to listen to
keeps me sane i have to admit while i
was making the mansion interior i've
been listening to the sherlock holmes
collection
read by stephen fry if you sign up to
audible you get a 30-day
free trial and you get one token every
month to purchase an audio book of your
choice
if you need something to keep you sane
at the moment then now is a pretty good
time to sign up to audible because
they've got a deal on
for the first six months it only costs
9.95
per month plus you get your 30 day free
trial and if you're interested there is
a link in the description
audible.com forward slash green or you
can text green to 500
500 and i would like to make a book
recommendation today
and that is red dwarf infinity welcomes
careful drivers
it is a very funny sci-fi
comedy which was written in the 90s so
it's not exactly a new book but it's one
of the few books that has made me
laugh out loud while listening to it and
i thoroughly enjoyed it it's read by
chris barry who does
really good impressions so i can't
recommend it enough it is
for more mature audiences so do be aware
of that so if you're interested remember
audible.com forward slash green or text
screen to 500
500 so that's a little bit behind the
scenes
let's get back into the video so
after that time lapse i have actually
achieved what i set out to do which is
to replicate
this part of the build on this side of
the mansion and there is a bug
or a drone why did i say it was a bug
there's a drone
in my base no pesky birds were harmed in
the making
of this oh no
you can't say you can't say that and
then re-actually rename it
has this been dispensing i think it has
i don't think i would have spotted the
chicken to be honest i think it's
dispensing on this balcony if anyone has
any idea what this is about
i would love to know there's another one
over there so we did achieve the build
that we wanted to do
the fact that audible sponsored another
hermitcraft video means that
you guys may have signed up from the
last one which is really really cool i
i honestly it is so so appreciated but
anyway i have had a message from impulse
saying that it is time to meet up with
him
at the secret base base there are a lot
of drones
a lot of weird drones so i'm gonna go
over to my secret base
at corrales base i need a better way of
phrasing this there's
too many bases so i need to go
and meet up with impulse and b-dubs
[Music]
welcome guys do my speakeasy
we have to be quiet though he can't hear
you
look corrales oh he can't hear
us he is right there though this was
supposed to be
my secret base but i've i've recently
discovered that i i think corrales might
be on to me but yeah you showed it in
your video dude
like what were you expecting yeah okay
i thought the viewers were gonna give
out the wrong information and confuse
them but
yeah i think he's on to us maybe
yeah i showed mine on video too by
actually oh my goodness
both of you need new secret bases you
can't show the audience because you
can't trust them
so both of you new secret bases this
one's a dud
we're in the danger zone right now i
know i'm just a nice guy
thank you real nice nice dad i worked so
hard on this place and now
it's just gonna get found well now it's
just free interior isn't it he's just
got just a free room it's a bit well i
mean it's a winner just win for corrales
really
exactly my gift to him is what it will
be there he goes okay
okay we can stand rest your knees good
good nice
so i wasn't finished in here though i
wanted to liven it up and like have
you know like people in here enjoying
beverages
has corrales found it yet no not that i
know of
okay well we should definitely leave him
a present because like at the moment
we've just done him a
well you've done him a great duty and
given him a free interior i think we
should
fill this thing with armor stands full
of corrales for funsies
with his face on it in here
is the corrales i love that with his
face i think he'll he'll appreciate that
he'll appreciate that the only issue is
i i have not got
any corrales heads i've got a lot of
beat ups heads
yeah yeah i'm in the same boat let's do
the thing we'll change
uh the skin our skin to corrales and
then we can like harvest each other's
face
like i do with b-dubs every now and
again oh that's a good idea
and if we all three do it we can get a
lot of them yes right okay
cool are you going to like put that put
that bed down and we'll uh oh oh look at
this look at this
i got i brought you one boom okay look
at that look see
okay right everyone change into corrales
and make sure he's okay
all right i've got some i got some
special swords as well for this
i have brought a special sword as well
i did not bring a special anything no
okay
this is hilarious what is this is the
best
okay everyone reset the spawn yep we're
good uh
just press tab for a second is that not
the most glorious thing
stinking tango cam ruining it all right
we have to do this while he's online
okay ready three two one
go hey i knew i yeah
you're wearing armor beat ups oh yeah
you got armor oh i got armor on
yeah let me take it off hold on
[Laughter]
oh red got him i put his wedding okay
oh you guys kind of yeah
yeah no mercy
we're making a lot of noise in here
he has all the swords we're sitting
ducks of course
we're gonna have to punch him to death
to get swords out of him oh yeah good
idea
there we go yes smart
i can't believe okay this is oh got him
give me some swords brian every single
time we do something like this i feel
like you get a sick enjoyment like
you're just smiling in silence
i got oh a lot i got let's see seven
here that means
no okay that's 23 i got 23 in my
inventory guys
that's enough surely that's enough
that is just so wrong
[Laughter]
can we just instead of doing the armor
stand thing why don't we just fill this
place with
corrales turtles does that not better
yeah i think that's a fantastic idea
oh yeah you're almost awake oh wait he's
gone he's good
okay let's turtle this oh my goodness
i've got loads of green dye let's craft
up some beds this is going to be
i don't know why i don't know how this
has ended up happening but it has
let's let's fill this thing with
corrales turtles
it's just too good to be true do you
think they would sit that way or do you
think they would sit
i don't know it's hard how would a
turtle sit
because yeah would you have it
like that look look he's got like the
head on sideways like that oh
yes sure sure sure
gotta work out the anatomy of corrales
turtles
i hear him flying around i know i know
every time i hear about rocket noise
it's terrifying
i'm gonna make this look like make it
look like they're having a little
discussion
what's what's the name of this place i
don't know i don't have a proper name
the sleeping turtle the sleeping chair
there you go
it's like the opposite of the sleeping
tone look at those eyes these eyes have
not slept
in years i've got to say dudes this is
like one of
the weirdest things that's happened in
hermitcraft it is
weird i'm i mean when when i logged in
today i didn't think this is where this
was going
oh these ones are like having a chat
with each other
yeah we'll make these guys have a chat
as well boom i'm out of crowded heads
we're done this is this is the best
thing
this is a mutant mutant one have you
ever seen the mutant turtle
oh yep well this is a nice surprise
the anticipation's killing me what's he
typing what you gonna say
hit enter green come on i'm dying over
here
i thought these updated in real time
that would be nice wouldn't it
then we could see all his typos yeah
that movie
all that typing i feel like he's gonna
need another sign yeah might need
another another time maybe oh i've just
been typing
[Music]
okay so i absolutely love it i actually
have something that we need to do at
my secret base um i think
i think that we're past the point of
even keeping it secret from each other
because last episode i was making my
secret base
b dubs just breaks through the wall well
this is over
like so i had to take my base down
before corrales had even seen it
so i was like what's the point i've made
a new secret base and i don't even think
there's any point
us hiding it from each other but i do
think we should link them up so
gonna do gonna do a clap and we're all
gonna cut to my base because i'm not
showing anyone the entrance you ready
three two one welcome to my secret base
wow this looks expensive it is i mean
it's bright
it's uh clean yes i got a nice i got a
nice hot tub in here
got my pesky bird you know it's just
chilling this is just flexing on my
wealth you know
i don't want to leave now my secret base
is currently unknown
to corrales and the audience so this one
is safe but you guys
both of you because you both showed your
bases
on the camera you need to make a new
secret base and so over here i've made
the start of a sewer system
was that part of the game
oh what's that part i think i lost
diamonds was that part of it
did i lose some diamonds from that oh
thank you i don't think
i don't think so oh i don't think he
lost any huh
what you got your hand there buddy oh
you can see it
can you guys there's a couple more
blocks that need to go there
that's all i got you did lose one i did
oh my god it got this i know you just
missed a spot
it's all good we got that taken care of
here we go i i'm lost a diamond block to
that
you know it's been such a long time
since anyone's died to creepers i'm i'm
shocked more than anything
okay well mine my secret base has its
own like little private tunnel
and i i mean i haven't actually built
the sewers but i can't be careful
i'm floating i made a tunnel
and uh so be good if you guys could link
up
your bases to the sewer system and then
well i have i have a plan but i will i
will tell you about the plan
later also i have to tell you i invited
etho ren
and scar but i don't know if they've
accepted
this could this could escalate how many
secret bases
if everybody joins well i mean six if
everyone joins in
plus the ones that got found yeah so i
mean every time we
find one that uh chris finds one we need
to make another right does that sound
good
that sounds fantastic yeah awesome
so now it's time for me to get to work
on this sewer
but look at the truck wow
i've never seen this before this city
is constantly surprising me his corrales
vehicle game is on point
but for now i'm afraid we've run out of
time
i have to go ahead and start making the
sewer system along with b dubs and
impulse
and hopefully we can get everyone's
bases it up
and then next episode i'm hoping i can
introduce a little thing
to make this a bit more interesting so
all there is left to say is
a huge thank you for watching the video
i hope you enjoyed all of it including
the bit where i showed you how difficult
it was to build grambot because
it genuinely was difficult and i don't
think i ever would have showed
on camera grumbot's different forms
without that sponsorship so you know got
a bit of the behind the scenes going on
so anyway i wanna say a massive thank
you for watching as always
and if you enjoyed the video consider
subscribing
don't say that very often but thank you
very much watching and i shall see you
in the next one good
bye
you